Dmytro Karataiev

adkdevelopment.com github.com/dmytroKarataiev linkedin.com/in/dmytrokarataiev

Summary:

Android developer with portfolio of open-source applications published on Google Play and interested in the field of Machine Learning, who believes in test-driven development and Clean approach to coding. Also have extensive experience in marketing, including successful portfolio management and new brands launches.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java. Databases/Other: Realm, SQLite, Git, Gradle, CI services. Android: Dagger 2, RxJava 2, MVP, TDD. Exposed to: Kotlin, JavaScript, Python.

Work Experience

F3 Software – Senior Android Developer

Los Angeles, USA | October 2016 – Present

- Leading a team of developers to continuously deliver, improve and extend a series of applications.
- Working closely with UI designers, business analysts and testers in a highly collaborative environment.
- Developing the architecture of apps and maintaining high crash free user percentage (>99%).

Freelance – Android Developer

Los Angeles, USA | August 2014 – September 2016

- Developed Android applications for clients according to their requirements.
- Worked under NDA on one health-related project and as a tester for an Android MOOC platform.

Yalantis - Android Intern - GitHub Page

Dnipro, Ukraine | February 2016 - June 2016

- Created three Android applications with an increasing level of complexity.
- Used technologies: MVP Architecture, RxJava, Retrofit, Facebook API, Dagger 2, etc.

DANONE Nutricia – Marketing, Strategy and Insights Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | April 2013 - August 2014

• Managed portfolio of 3 brands, achieved 2nd position in the Value Market Share (+700bps Year on Year).

Unilever – Brand Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | July 2010 – April 2013

Achieved 1st place in Volume/Value Market Shares (+1000bps), launched new brand, 40 additional SKU's.

Project Experience

Machine Learning Nanodegree projects - GitHub Page

June 2016 - November 2016

• Completed projects on Supervised (Boston Housing Prices, Student Intervention System), Unsupervised (Creating Customer Segments) and Reinforcement learning (Smartcab).

Earthquake Survival - GitHub Page - Google Play

April 2016 - Present

- Earthquake monitoring application with survival information, notifications, auto syncs.
- Uses SyncAdapter, ContentProvider, Loaders, Maps, Locations, Geofences, Notifications, RxJava, Retrofit.

The Movie Database - GitHub Page - Google Play

December 2015 - Present

- Fast and efficient client to The Movie Database with Search and Favorites functionality and tablet design.
- Uses ContentProvider, YouTube API, RxJava, Retrofit.

BBC News Reader - GitHub Page - Google Play

August 2016

- RSS news reader for the BBC XML feed.
- Uses MVP Architecture, Realm database, JobScheduler, RxJava, Retrofit.

Morse Flashlight - GitHub Page - Google Play

January 2016

- Flashlight application with simple design, fast speed, Morse code and an Emergency Signal.
- Works as Service with all the tasks on background thread (Service, Camera2 API).

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, USA – Computer Science, M.S.	2017-2020 (exp.)
Udacity – Android Developer Nanodegree - <u>Verified certificate</u>	April 2016
Taurida National University, Simferopol, Ukraine – Political Science, M.A.	June 2010

Certificates

edX MIT – 6.005.1-2x, Advanced Software construction in Java	September 2016 – April 2017
Coursera University of Michigan – Programming in Python (4 courses)	October 2015 – March 2016
Coursera Stanford – Algorithms and Analysis (Part 1)	October 2015 – December 2015
edX MIT – 6.00.1x, 6.00.2x Computer Science and Python Programming	August 2015 – December 2015

Honors and Activities

Udacity Transcend Award

Choice of the year award for the best brand in the market (2011, 2012)

First prize and diploma for the best paper – Moscow State University International Conference

April 2010